<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Accelerator | The Iron Yard]]></title>
  <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/categories/accelerator/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-07T23:11:37-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://theironyard.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The Iron Yard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Iron Yard Demo Days - Spring 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/05/26/the-iron-yard-demo-days-spring-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-26T20:10:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/05/26/the-iron-yard-demo-days-spring-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After three amazing, difficult, and rewarding months, our Spring 2013 Accelerator teams are ready to share their products with the world—and investors.</p>

<p>This year we&rsquo;ll launch on our home turf at the Grok conference, then hit the road and head to west, northeast, and back into the heartland of the south for pitch sessions.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;d love for you to join us at any point along the way. Here&rsquo;s a list of our demo days. Scroll down for details.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><strong>May 30th @ 2pm EST</strong> &ndash; Demo Day at the Grok Conference (<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367073087">RSVP</a>)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>June 3rd @ 10:30am PST</strong> &ndash; Morning Demo Session at Silicon Valley Bank (<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367422131">RSVP</a>)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>June 3rd @ 3:30pm PST</strong> &ndash; Afternoon Demo Session at Silicon Valley Bank (<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6458903755">RSVP</a>)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>June 4th @ various times</strong> &ndash; Launch: Silicon Valley (<a href="https://svforum.org/Launch-Silicon-Valley/Launch-Silicon-Valley-2013">Register</a>)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>June 11th @ 10:00am EST</strong> &ndash; Demo Day in Boston (<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6312983303">RSVP</a>)</p></li>
<li><p><strong>June 12-13 @ various times EST</strong> &ndash; Startup Village at Southland Startup Conference (<a href="http://www.southlandse.com/">Register</a>)</p></li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3>Grok &ndash; May 30th</h3>

<p>Our Grok Demo Day event is on the afternoon of May 30th. Join 200 conference attendees, plus investors, mentors and press to celebrate our teams' completion of the accelerator.</p>

<p><em>2 North Main
Greenville, SC 29601</em>
<em><a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=2+north+main,+Greenville,+sc&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=37.788446,-122.398641&amp;sspn=0.092113,0.181789&amp;t=v&amp;hnear=2+N+Main+St,+Greenville,+South+Carolina+29601&amp;z=16">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>[button url=&ldquo;<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367073087">http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367073087</a>&rdquo; target=&ldquo;_blank&rdquo; label=&ldquo;RSVP for May 30th at 2:00pm EST&rdquo;]</p>

<hr />

<h3>West Coast Trip &ndash; June 3-7</h3>

<p><strong>June 3rd</strong>
We&rsquo;ll pitch twice on Monday at the SVB offices on Mission St.</p>

<p><em>555 Mission Street
San Francisco, CA 94105</em>
<em><a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=silicon+valley+bank,+mission+st.+san+francisco&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=33.624497,-80.926614&amp;sspn=6.209617,11.634521&amp;t=v&amp;hq=silicon+valley+bank,&amp;hnear=Mission+St,+San+Francisco,+California&amp;z=13&amp;iwloc=A">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>[button url=&ldquo;<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367422131">http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367422131</a>&rdquo; target=&ldquo;_blank&rdquo; label=&ldquo;RSVP for June 3rd at 10:30am PST&rdquo;]</p>

<p>[button url=&ldquo;<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6458903755">http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6458903755</a>&rdquo; target=&ldquo;_blank&rdquo; label=&ldquo;RSVP for June 3rd at 3:30pm PST&rdquo;]</p>

<p><strong>June 4th</strong>
A few of our teams will be pitching at <a href="http://launchsiliconvalley.org/">Launch: Silicon Valley</a> and have displays at the expo.</p>

<p><em>Microsoft Campus (Mountain View)
1065 La Avenida
Mountain View, CA 94043</em>
<em><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=1065+La+Avenida+Mountain+View,+CA+94043&amp;hnear=1065+La+Avenida+St,+Mountain+View,+Santa+Clara,+California+94043&amp;gl=us&amp;t=v&amp;z=16https://maps.google.com/maps?q=1065+La+Avenida+Mountain+View,+CA+94043&amp;hnear=1065+La+Avenida+St,+Mountain+View,+Santa+Clara,+California+94043&amp;gl=us&amp;t=v&amp;z=16">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>[button url=&ldquo;<a href="https://svforum.org/Launch-Silicon-Valley/Launch-Silicon-Valley-2013">https://svforum.org/Launch-Silicon-Valley/Launch-Silicon-Valley-2013</a>&rdquo; target=&ldquo;_blank&rdquo; label=&ldquo;Register for Launch: Silicon Valley on June 4th&rdquo;]</p>

<hr />

<h3>East Coast Trip &ndash; June 10-11</h3>

<p><strong>June 11th</strong>
Our teams will present at Microsoft NERD on Tuesday, June 11th.</p>

<p><em>Sampson/Paul Theater
1 Memorial Dr #1
Cambridge, MA ‎ 02142</em>
<em><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=Microsoft+New+England+Research+and+Development+Center,+Memorial+Drive,+Cambridge,+MA&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=37.410801,-122.072396&amp;sspn=0.011573,0.022724&amp;oq=microsoft+nerd&amp;t=v&amp;gl=us&amp;hq=Microsoft+New+England+Research+and+Development+Center,+Memorial+Drive,+Cambridge,+MA&amp;z=15">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>[button url=&ldquo;<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6312983303">http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6312983303</a>&rdquo; target=&ldquo;_blank&rdquo; label=&ldquo;RSVP for June 11th at 10:00am EST&rdquo;]</p>

<hr />

<h3>Southland Conference &ndash; June 12-13</h3>

<p>We&rsquo;ll be hanging out at the Southeast&rsquo;s premier tech conference, <a href="http://www.southlandse.com/">Southland</a>.</p>

<p><em>One Cannery Row
Nashville, TN. 37203</em>
<em><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=One+Cannery+Row+Nashville,+TN.+37203&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=42.361315,-71.081309&amp;sspn=0.021531,0.045447&amp;t=v&amp;gl=us&amp;hnear=1+Cannery+Row,+Nashville,+Davidson,+Tennessee+37203&amp;z=16">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>[button url=&ldquo;<a href="http://www.southlandse.com/">http://www.southlandse.com/</a>&rdquo; target=&ldquo;_blank&rdquo; label=&ldquo;Register for Southland on June 12-13&rdquo;]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startups Need Conviction]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/05/09/startups-need-conviction/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T12:13:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/05/09/startups-need-conviction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Startup Life™ is thickly shrouded with threats of difficulty. First you&rsquo;re required to have an astoundingly novel idea that promises to capture a gigantic industry or market. (Or at least be able to convince people of those things.) Next, you need a killer team, preferably one with a brilliant engineer co-founder who&rsquo;s willing to give up a six-figure income to work tirelessly on your product.</p>

<p>Later you discover that the importance of the idea pales in comparison to execution: if you can&rsquo;t ship, you&rsquo;re dead in the water. Courting VCs and negotiating term sheets, if you&rsquo;re one of the lucky few to beat that many levels and face the boss, is a black art in and of itself, and one wrong step can flush everything you&rsquo;ve worked for down the drain. Work/life balance as most know isn&rsquo;t even part of the equation for many entrepreneurs.</p>

<p>After running an accelerator program for 7 months, though, I&rsquo;ve learned that one of the most trying hurdles is the minefield of different &lsquo;advice&rsquo; startups get along the way.</p>

<p>Early stage companies &ndash; especially those in mentorship-driven programs &ndash; face an inordinate flood of conflicting opinions on every aspect of their company. From inconsequential design details to overall strategy, teams can receive unending praise and completely deflating interrogation in the same day. Both types of feedback come from successful people who&rsquo;s resumés command a level of respect.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t have strong conviction about your product and company, incongruous advice can toss you like a row boat in a hurricane. If you question your your compass enough times, it can be hard to remember why you started the journey in the first place.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s true that stubbornness has killed many companies, but requiring clear and convincing evidence to change has made some of the most successful businesses in the world just that.</p>

<p>There is no lack of smart people, good ideas, and money to put behind them. My bet will be on teams with real conviction.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Southern Culture & Technology]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/04/22/southern-culture-technology/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T14:42:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/04/22/southern-culture-technology</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We live and work in the South, and we love it. One of our favorite things is how surprised people get when they come visit &ndash; assumptions melt away and they find a thriving culture and growing tech scene.</p>

<p>Some of our friends up in Tennessee are wrapping as much of those ingredients in to one event as possible, and we&rsquo;re joining them. On June 12th and 13th, we&rsquo;re headed to Nashville for <a href="http://www.southlandse.com/">Southland</a>, a conference where we&rsquo;ll be connecting the Southeast&rsquo;s best early-stage companies with investors from across the country.</p>

<p>Come watch our region&rsquo;s hand-picked startups pitch, meet VCs and Angels from around the country, world class speakers, and of course, a full does of Southern music and food.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re already going, <a href="mailto:hello@theironyard.com?subject=I'm%20coming%20to%20Southland%20and%20would%20love%20to%20meet%20up">let us know</a>. We&rsquo;d love to meet you at the event.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iron Yard Alum Spent Focuses on Relevance and Releases First Product: "Relify"]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/02/13/iron-yard-alum-spent-focuses-on-relevance-and-releases-first-product-relify/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-13T15:57:33-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/02/13/iron-yard-alum-spent-focuses-on-relevance-and-releases-first-product-relify</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s no secret that consumer demand for personalized products and experiences is increasing at incredible speed, and that demand is creating new standards.</p>

<blockquote><p>Nobody gets this perfect, because humans don’t make sense. Our tastes are not neatly defined. I legitimately enjoy listening to D’Angelo, Nickelback and Huey Lewis so… good luck with music suggestions for me, Rdio. Lo, I Am Become Enigma, Destroyer of Algorithms. Netflix or Amazon regularly suggest the most ridiculous things to me. But they’re trying. Tweaking. Spending millions of man hours and dollars to improve those algorithms by 1%, because 1% more relevant is a massive improvement. —<a href="http://joshuablankenship.com/blog/2012/08/14/how-tripit-and-zynga-are-blowing-it-with-my-data/">Joshua Blankenship</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Spent, one of our alumni, is excited about this trend, and they&rsquo;re building products that will help all types of companies provide relevance to their users.</p>

<p>Their team set out to build a recommendation engine for the grocery industry, allowing stores to offer personalized offers based on customer purchase behavior. As they dug into the world of relevance, though they realized how powerful the technology could be for just about any industry.</p>

<p>They took a few steps back, built their product as an API anyone can use, and <a href="https://www.relify.com/index">Relify</a> was born as their first product.</p>

<p>Relify provides recommendations as a service and is geared towards developers, offering quick and easy integration with their apps:</p>

<p>_&ldquo;Relify eliminates the complexity of building a recommendation engine from scratch, and makes it simple for companies to use the data they already have to reduce the paradox of choice. The solution fits companies that track data about their customers but don’t understand how to use it, or don’t have the resources to tackle building their own recommendation engine.</p>

<p>Relify’s technology uses existing recommendation algorithms, combined with proprietary methods, to quickly analyze data and serve recommendations. Using data generated from everyday activities like buying groceries or browsing the Internet, recommendations are personalized for each user. Developers import their data, create data sets and use recommenders to customize the types of recommendations they use in their applications.&ldquo;_</p>

<p><a href="https://www.relify.com/docs/api/1/use_cases">Check out a few use cases</a> from the documentation, and be sure to check out the <a href="https://developers.relify.com/index">product</a> and <a href="https://developers.relify.com/pricing">pricing</a>.</p>

<p>Congrats, Spent, and hello Relify!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello MoonClerk! Iron Yard Alumni Announces Public Product Launch]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/02/06/hello-moonclerk-iron-yard-alumni-announces-public-product-launch/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T17:35:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/02/06/hello-moonclerk-iron-yard-alumni-announces-public-product-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ask any small business and they&rsquo;ll tell you that accepting recurring payments is either a huge hassle, overly expensive, or probably both. Sure, there are awesome point of sale tools for almost any type of vendor (Square, etc.), but if your business runs any type of subscription based product or service, you&rsquo;re probably in for a headache.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://www.moonclerk.com/">MoonClerk</a>, Iron Yard 2012 alumni.</p>

<p>Dodd Caldwell, the founder, was really fed up with having to either develop fully custom payment solutions for each new project, or use  existing providers that were painful to work with (ahem, PayPal, ahem). So he decided to solve the problem from the ground up.</p>

<p>In a sentence, here&rsquo;s what it does:</p>

<blockquote><p>MoonClerk is a web-based service designed to help small businesses easily accept recurring and one-time online payments.</p></blockquote>

<p>&ldquo;But they can already do that!&rdquo; you say. True, but not without a lot of difficulty or a lot of money. In fact, you don&rsquo;t have to have any technical capability to use MoonClerk. It differentiates itself from e-commerce solutions and point-of-sale systems such as Square by allowing businesses to gather credit card information from their customer or donors and then charging that credit card on a recurring or subscription basis.</p>

<p>And, it&rsquo;s amazingly easy to set up and use:</p>

<blockquote><p>Businesses can set up MoonClerk without any technical or programming skills. The entire setup process generally takes around 5 minutes to begin accepting payments because there are no merchant accounts, payment gateways, or other systems to apply for and implement. MoonClerk provides bank-level security so businesses don&rsquo;t need to deal with SSL certificates or PCI compliance. Checkout works on all devices &ndash; desktop and mobile.</p></blockquote>

<p>Not only that, but it automates some of the annoying administrative tasks associtated with running a small business:</p>

<blockquote><p>So, for instance, a lawn care service can set a customer up on-site with a subscription payment and then forget about having to send and collect on invoices. We also help them with some of the back-office issues, like sending out automatic receipts.</p></blockquote>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what Dodd had to say about building the product:</p>

<blockquote><p>When my co-founder, Ryan Wood, and I decided to build MoonClerk, we really wanted to help businesses convert customers. When someone decides to pay you or donate to you, you want them to complete the process. By giving our customers control of the design of the checkout experience and other great tools, we&rsquo;re able to help them accomplish that goal. PayPal was one of the only recurring systems out there for small businesses and it didn&rsquo;t really allow non-technical users to do that.</p></blockquote>

<p>How much does it cost? MoonClerk piggybacks on payment processor Stripe. Businesses can set up a Stripe account while activating their MoonClerk accounts. Funds are automatically transferred into the business&rsquo;s bank account, and pricing starts at $9/month. Stripe charges 2.9% + $.30 per successful transaction.</p>

<p>Three cheers for an amazing product, Dodd and Ryan.</p>

<p><em>Want more? Visit <a href="http://www.moonclerk.com/">www.moonclerk.com</a> or contact Dodd Caldwell at dodd(at)moonclerk(dot)com</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
