<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Academy | The Iron Yard]]></title>
  <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/categories/academy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-07T15:41:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://theironyard.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The Iron Yard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Progress Report: The Iron Yard Academy's First Class]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/06/26/progress-report-the-iron-yard-academys-first-class/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-26T15:58:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/06/26/progress-report-the-iron-yard-academys-first-class</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;re nearing the end of our first Front End Engineering course, and it&rsquo;s been an amazing experience. Halfway through the course we talked to both students and guest lecturers to see what they had to say. Here are a few responses.</p>

<hr />

<h3>Guest Design Instructor – Marco Suarez</h3>

<p>We invited our friend Marco, now an Art Director at MailChimp, to spend a week teaching our Front End Engineering students about design. He gave them crash courses on everything from color theory and design thinking to responsive web design techniques.</p>

<p>After the class we asked him what he thought about the students, and he told us they&rsquo;re the type of talent he&rsquo;s looking to hire. Take it away, Marco:</p>

<hr />

<h3>Student – Andrew McIntee</h3>

<p>Andrew McIntee started working as a front end developer in high school. After graduation, he tried college, but decided that jumping into a design career would be more satisfying. As he gained experience he noticed that his value to clients could increase dramatically if he could both design and develop digital products.</p>

<p>He came to The Iron Yard Academy&rsquo;s Front End Engineering course to increase his code chops, and says that three months here has been worth three years in his career. He&rsquo;s busy with freelance work, but is ready for a full time job at a cool company. Hire while it&rsquo;s hot. Here&rsquo;s Andrew telling his story:</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What We Learned Starting an Intensive Design Class]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/05/04/what-we-learned-starting-an-intensive-design-class/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-04T09:41:58-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/05/04/what-we-learned-starting-an-intensive-design-class</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a post from Marco Suarez explaining what we&rsquo;ve learned on the journey of starting an intensive design school.</em></p>

<p>There is a gap that is widening between the education students are receiving and the skills companies require. The most obvious disconnect is in software and technology. Universities fail to keep up and the proponents of an informal, self-taught education use that deficiency as their banner. But technology and software are platforms and tools. And just because you know how to use a tool doesn’t make you a craftsman. The more serious gap is in a person’s ability to think. Mobile touch platforms have radically changed the way we use technology, so much so that it has caused broad societal shift. The potential of this shift is fueling investors to pour insane amounts of money into people and ideas that take advantage of it. There is a need for designers who can think critically and creatively to solve real problems by utilizing these new platforms and tools.</p>

<p>And this is where The Iron Yard comes into the story. The Iron Yard is a company in the southeast that has set up residence at the gates of new tech ideation. And we saw an opportunity. We know software and technology really well and we know companies that are hiring. So we started an <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/education/academy/front-end-engineering">intensive front end engineering program</a> this year that is doing great. So great that we decided to spin up a <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/education/academy/product-design">design program</a> that focuses on digital product design. We’d teach the process of design thinking through building real applications for real people. We’d assess problems and build prototypes, brands, and interfaces for web and mobile. Sounded like a home run. So we thought.</p>

<p>The vast differences between teaching code and design &ndash; and recruiting students for each discipline &ndash; taught us a lot about the state of education. Teaching code is similar to teaching math—either you know it or you don’t. Design is different. It’s subjective. It assembles culture, metaphors, art, and taste with problems, challenges, and data. So you could say it is similar to teaching English. A lot of people think they’re good enough at English that they don’t need to further their learning of the language.</p>

<p>Another observation is the people in our front end engineering program didn’t have any previous experience with code, and they didn’t need to. After a month of class, they were as proficient as me and I’ve been doing this stuff for a decade. Kudos to their teacher, Mason Stewart. But our design program wasn’t a foundational design course. It was a higher learning program that would add another tool to their design toolbox. This changed our target market drastically. In the pool of designers, we were targeting those who wanted to shift out of designing consumables (websites, advertising, and marketing) to designing software for startups. So our task was to get our program in front of those people.</p>

<p>We tried some PR, social media, and whatever else but to no avail. And then we remembered <a href="http://blog.theironyard.com/2013/04/the-gap-or-why-we-started-a-design-course/">the gap</a>. Universities do a good job giving students a solid design foundation. They give students four years to get it wrong, experiment, and expand their minds. This was a foundation we could build on. So we scheduled some meetings with local universities and found an overwhelmingly positive response to what we were offering. Universities recognize where they’re falling short and supplementing their program with ours seemed like a match made in heaven. So we narrowed our focus to students. This is where it got interesting.</p>

<p>I assumed that this technologically saturated generation would be so starved for digital literacy that our program would be cool water to their lips. But I could not have been more wrong. These students all owned iPhones, Androids, and tablets and computers of all kinds. They’re all active users on Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, and all sorts of apps but none of them had ever thought they could work for one of these companies. When I mentioned that we would be learning to write some code, I completely lost them. At that point our class was not only foreign, it was intimidating. And who is going to sign away three months of their lives and a bunch of money to be intimidated and frustrated and then be placed in an ever more intimidating and frustrating job?</p>

<p>Two weeks away from the inaugural launch of our class, we had two signups. We approached students just weeks away from graduation about pretty much changing the trajectory of their career. Not such a good idea. In order to create action you have to first reveal the need for action. And we were asking these students to act before they fully realized the need. We were a little overzealous. But we believe the greatest need for our program is in bridging the gap between universities and companies.And now that we know our target market, we can form a plan that entices students early on, accommodates their schedules and budgets, and place them in jobs where they can fully utilize their minds and their knowledge of software and technology.</p>

<p>We’re working out ideas like one day classes on Saturdays, classes that fit into a normal semester, and the summer long intensive program with a guaranteed job placement. Whatever the end product looks like, the need is growing, and The Iron Yard is passionate about training the next generation of great designers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Gap (or Why We Started a Design Course)]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/the-gap-or-why-we-started-a-design-course/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-02T16:48:32-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/04/02/the-gap-or-why-we-started-a-design-course</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><em>From our Product Design instructor, <a href="http://twitter.com/marcosuarez">Marco</a>:</em></p>

<p>Education is a hot topic. Does the value of a diploma out weight the ever-rising cost of tuition? I think the answer is overwhelmingly yes for some careers. But not all. In the world of design, what you’ve done carries more weight than where you went to school. That has been a known truth for quite some years. But with the advent of smart phones and tablets, the demand for qualified digital product designers has seen an unprecedented uptick. So how are designers learning these lucrative skills?</p>

<p>Universities excel at offering strong foundations of design theory, peer collaboration, and a period of focus and dedication, but at a mortgage level price tag.The problem is not only the cost; universities struggle to keep up with how quickly the design industry evolves. Never before has design been so tightly melded with technology. Terms like user experience, mobile design and interface design are becoming commonplace on design job boards but largely absent in curriculums.</p>

<p>Online learning has been evolving over the last few years to supplement, if not replace a formal education. These programs have growth rates that would make any CEO green with envy. Their model is a nominal monthly fee in exchange for video tutorials and projects that educate the viewer on cutting edge trends in website and app development. But where these programs excel at teaching the latest software and technology, they lack in one-on-one guidance, emphasis on design theory, and in-person collaboration with other students.</p>

<p>So are these the only options? Is there not something that fits in the gap between these avenues of education? We think so. And that’s what we&rsquo;re building at The Iron Yard. This year we started an <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/education/academy">Academy</a>, offering affordable, accessible three-month-intensive classes in Greenville, SC. We just started a front-end engineering class and we’re gearing up to start a <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/education/academy/product-design">digital product design class this May</a>.</p>

<p>Our digital product design course will teach students the process of design thinking, how to develop ideas based on data and observation, create and test prototypes, build brands, design interfaces for web and mobile, and teach them cutting-edge technology and software.</p>

<p>They’ll have one-on-one guidance from a seasoned professional designer, work collaboratively and individually, and tackle live projects that benefit real people.They’ll have exposure to startups in our accelerator program and opportunities to meet and learn from some of the best and brightest designers in the industry. (Course mentors include Matthew Smith, Aaron Walter, and Josh Brewer.)</p>

<p>We will provide housing just down the road from our facility in downtown Greenville and a bike for transportation. All day-to-day necessities are in walking distance. We’ll also provide a brand new Apple laptop and access to Adobe’s Creative Cloud during the course &ndash; that way our students can focus all their attention on the course and projects.</p>

<p>Our mission is not to replace a formal education nor the need for online learning, but fill a gap that our shifting industry has created, train people for great jobs, and build meaningful projects in the process.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Iron Yard Academy: Front End Engineering Class Applications are OPEN]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/02/22/the-iron-yard-academy-front-end-engineering-class-applications-are-open/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-22T13:56:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/02/22/the-iron-yard-academy-front-end-engineering-class-applications-are-open</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the last month we&rsquo;ve been working on a project called The Iron Yard Academy, and we&rsquo;re excited to announce that <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/academy/apply">applications are open</a> for our <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/academy/the-iron-yard-academy">Front End Engineering</a> class.</p>

<p><strong>What is this Iron Yard Academy, you ask?</strong></p>

<p>The Academy is a collection of intensive, in-person programming and design courses, built to take students from zero to hero in a short amount of time. When they complete the program, we&rsquo;ll help place them in a job. Other schools like this exist, but not in the Southeast.</p>

<p><strong>What subjects will you teach?</strong></p>

<p>We&rsquo;ve opened applications for our three-month Front End Engineering class, and will launch a UX/UI course later this spring. We hope to add iOS and Rails courses later in the year.</p>

<p><strong>What kind of instructors are teaching these classes?</strong></p>

<p>Our Front End instructor (and the head of our Academy program) is <a href="http://twitter.com/masondesu">Mason Stewart</a>. He&rsquo;s a seasoned engineer, and he&rsquo;s worked for small, Southern boutique web shops, startups from San Francisco to Greenville, and everywhere in between. He also heads up <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/academy/kids">CoderDojo Greenville</a>, teaching over 40 kids per week how to program in Scratch and JavaScript. (Check out a <a href="http://vimeo.com/58981618#at=0">video from the class</a>.)</p>

<p>Also, we can&rsquo;t say who just quite yet, but we recently hired a genius-level instructor for our upcoming UX/UI class. More news on that soon.</p>

<p><strong>What will students be ready for after taking the courses?</strong></p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what we&rsquo;ll prepare students for in the Front End class:</p>

<p>You will be qualified as a professional, junior-level JavaScript and front-end engineer.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Join a startup and get a solid prototype off the ground quickly and efficiently</p></li>
<li><p>Build digital products for web development shop, agency, etc.</p></li>
<li><p>Build non-trivial, fast, efficient, production-quality apps</p></li>
<li><p>Build gorgeous websites</p></li>
<li><p>Most importantly, learn how to learn</p></li>
</ul>


<p>You won&rsquo;t know absolutely everything there is to know, but we will ensure that you <em>know how to learn it</em> if you need to.</p>

<p><strong>Ok, fancy pants, how much will this cost?</strong></p>

<p>$9,750, including housing and a MacBook air that you get to keep. For real.</p>

<p><strong>CAN I APPLY RIGHT NOW??</strong></p>

<p>Absolutely. <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/academy/the-iron-yard-academy">Head over to our website</a>, read about the course, and <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/academy/apply">sign on up</a>. We&rsquo;ve had lots of strong applicants already, so get it while it&rsquo;s hot.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CoderDojo Greenville Live! ]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/02/05/coderdojo-greenville-live/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-05T11:18:16-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/02/05/coderdojo-greenville-live</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&rsquo;ve talked a lot about our <a href="http://www.theironyard.com/academy/kids">CoderDojo program</a> for kids, and we&rsquo;ve even shared <a href="http://blog.theironyard.com/2013/01/getting-to-their-level-teaching-kids-to-code/">great stories</a> we&rsquo;ve experienced along the way.</p>

<p>We recently had <a href="http://chrisbrankfilms.com/">Chris Brank</a> and his team fire up the video cameras so you could see what it looks like live.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
