<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Announcements | The Iron Yard]]></title>
  <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/categories/announcements/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://theironyard.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-20T11:17:46-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://theironyard.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The Iron Yard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Happy Birthday Peter! ]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/02/19/happy-birthday-peter/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-19T11:14:49-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/02/19/happy-birthday-peter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Iron Yard wouldn&rsquo;t be what it is without you, Pete.</p>

<p><strong>Happy Birthday!</strong></p>

<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/02/900x900px-LL-89c85861_IMG_3551.jpeg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>We hope that you never tire of us Photoshopping your face on stuff.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello MoonClerk! Iron Yard Alumni Announces Public Product Launch]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/02/06/hello-moonclerk-iron-yard-alumni-announces-public-product-launch/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-06T17:35:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/02/06/hello-moonclerk-iron-yard-alumni-announces-public-product-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/02/moonclerk-launch.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p>Ask any small business and they&rsquo;ll tell you that accepting recurring payments is either a huge hassle, overly expensive, or probably both. Sure, there are awesome point of sale tools for almost any type of vendor (Square, etc.), but if your business runs any type of subscription based product or service, you&rsquo;re probably in for a headache.</p>

<p>Enter <a href="http://www.moonclerk.com/">MoonClerk</a>, Iron Yard 2012 alumni.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Dodd Caldwell, the founder, was really fed up with having to either develop fully custom payment solutions for each new project, or use  existing providers that were painful to work with (ahem, PayPal, ahem). So he decided to solve the problem from the ground up.</p>

<p>In a sentence, here&rsquo;s what it does:</p>

<blockquote><p>MoonClerk is a web-based service designed to help small businesses easily accept recurring and one-time online payments.</p></blockquote>

<p>&ldquo;But they can already do that!&rdquo; you say. True, but not without a lot of difficulty or a lot of money. In fact, you don&rsquo;t have to have any technical capability to use MoonClerk. It differentiates itself from e-commerce solutions and point-of-sale systems such as Square by allowing businesses to gather credit card information from their customer or donors and then charging that credit card on a recurring or subscription basis.</p>

<p>And, it&rsquo;s amazingly easy to set up and use:</p>

<blockquote><p>Businesses can set up MoonClerk without any technical or programming skills. The entire setup process generally takes around 5 minutes to begin accepting payments because there are no merchant accounts, payment gateways, or other systems to apply for and implement. MoonClerk provides bank-level security so businesses don&rsquo;t need to deal with SSL certificates or PCI compliance. Checkout works on all devices &ndash; desktop and mobile.</p></blockquote>

<p>Not only that, but it automates some of the annoying administrative tasks associtated with running a small business:</p>

<blockquote><p>So, for instance, a lawn care service can set a customer up on-site with a subscription payment and then forget about having to send and collect on invoices. We also help them with some of the back-office issues, like sending out automatic receipts.</p></blockquote>

<p>Here&rsquo;s what Dodd had to say about building the product:</p>

<blockquote><p>When my co-founder, Ryan Wood, and I decided to build MoonClerk, we really wanted to help businesses convert customers. When someone decides to pay you or donate to you, you want them to complete the process. By giving our customers control of the design of the checkout experience and other great tools, we&rsquo;re able to help them accomplish that goal. PayPal was one of the only recurring systems out there for small businesses and it didn&rsquo;t really allow non-technical users to do that.</p></blockquote>

<p>How much does it cost? MoonClerk piggybacks on payment processor Stripe. Businesses can set up a Stripe account while activating their MoonClerk accounts. Funds are automatically transferred into the business&rsquo;s bank account, and pricing starts at $9/month. Stripe charges 2.9% + $.30 per successful transaction.</p>

<p>Three cheers for an amazing product, Dodd and Ryan.</p>

<p><em>Want more? Visit <a href="http://www.moonclerk.com/">www.moonclerk.com</a> or contact Dodd Caldwell at dodd(at)moonclerk(dot)com</em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome Kevin Crace, Designer in Residence]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/01/28/welcome-kevin-crace-designer-in-residence/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-28T09:18:17-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/01/28/welcome-kevin-crace-designer-in-residence</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/01/kevin-crace-intro.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p><em>At the end of 2012, we were lucky enough to get an email from a guy named Kevin Crace. He was finishing up at Boston Startup School after crushing through an architecture degree from <a href="http://www.risd.edu/">RISD</a>, all before he made it through age 25. If that wasn&rsquo;t enough, he&rsquo;s done great freelance work for startups like <a href="http://www.promoboxx.com/">Promoboxx</a> and <a href="http://dashbell.com/">Dashbell</a>. Turns out he&rsquo;s passionate about the Southeast, and he wanted help out at The Iron Yard. We&rsquo;ve already gotten his hands dirty with Iron Yard design projects, and we can&rsquo;t wait to see the incredible stuff he does for our startups.</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Meet Kevin:</p>

<p>A quick hello from your friendly neighborhood designer-in-residence,</p>

<p>So here I am in Greenville, SC by way of Boston and I gotta say that I am loving it, <em>y’all</em>. I just wrapped up with <a href="http://bostonstartupschool.com/">Boston Startup School</a> where I was submerged in all things startup. I learned the lingo, the series, the culture fit, the hugs, and the sweat equity, but most importantly I learned about risk.</p>

<p>After rapidly building a network in Boston and meeting with many fresh startups, I realized how much community is valued. I decided to take a risk and leave Boston for a community I feel rooted to and a community I want to see thrive. I am thrilled to be a part of The Iron Yard because they have the same value and drive.  We’re here to see the Upstate thrive and to weave in rich pockets of tech and design.</p>

<p>I can’t wait to get my design hands dirty with the companies coming through the accelerator. I am eager to be a sponge for each mentor that walks in (call me SpongeBob Khaki Pants) and I am ready to immerse myself in the startup world of the Carolinas.</p>

<p>Here we go (high fives all around)!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Year, New Look, and New Faces]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/01/03/new-year-new-look-and-new-faces/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-03T12:17:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/01/03/new-year-new-look-and-new-faces</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/01/new-site-2.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p>We have some great New Year&rsquo;s surprises for you.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h4>1) We re-branded.</h4>

<p>Over the past few months we&rsquo;ve worked with the uber-talented <a href="http://www.justinhalldesign.com/">Justin Hall</a> to refine the look and feel of our brand. We&rsquo;re really excited about our new outfit, and we&rsquo;ll write in more detail about the process in the coming weeks.</p>

<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/01/the-iron-yard-logo-e1357233395984.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px; border: 1px solid gray;"></p>

<h4>2) We launched a new website.</h4>

<p>Along with the brand, we&rsquo;ve just pushed a shiny <a href="http://theironyard.com">new site</a> live. It&rsquo;s hot off the Rails, so let us know if you find any quirks.</p>

<h4>3) We have some new faces in the office.</h4>

<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/01/kate-mccarthy-e1357233252598.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p>I realized that we forgot to officially announce my arrival on the blog, so we&rsquo;ll say this counts.</p>

<p>More importantly, though, we&rsquo;ve brought on Kate McCarthy as our Spartanburg program manager. She&rsquo;s awesome.</p>

<p><em>&ldquo;WAIT, Spartanburg??&rdquo;</em> you say? Yes, Spartanburg. We&rsquo;re excited to announce that we&rsquo;ll run a second accelerator classes this year focused on healthcare IT.</p>

<h4>Happy New Year from The Iron Yard!</h4>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
