<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Upstate SC | The Iron Yard]]></title>
  <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/categories/upstate-sc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-08-08T10:13:20-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://theironyard.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The Iron Yard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Made the Front Page of Local News Beside an Unrelated Article About Downton Abbey]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/01/14/eric-made-the-front-page-of-local-news-beside-an-unrelated-article-about-downton-abbey/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-14T12:02:30-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2013/01/14/eric-made-the-front-page-of-local-news-beside-an-unrelated-article-about-downton-abbey</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is totally not important, but it is.</p>

<p><a href="http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/eric-greenville-news-1.9.131.jpg"><img src="http://blog.theironyard.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/01/eric-greenville-news-1.9.131.jpg" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[South Carolina is Attracting Capital]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2012/11/26/south-carolina-is-attracting-capital/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T08:41:52-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2012/11/26/south-carolina-is-attracting-capital</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>South Carolina traditionally has struggled to garner as much venture capital as densely urban, high-tech areas, such as Austin, Boston, New York City or Silicon Valley.</p></blockquote>

<p><strong>But one Silicon Valley investor has taken notice of Greenville, and a few Palmetto State startups have attracted capital recently.</strong></p>

<p>–GSA Business, <a href="http://www.gsabusiness.com/news/45945-venture-capitalists-take-a-peek-at-s-c">Venture capitalists take a peek at S.C.</a></p>

<p>South Carolina is attracting capital, and we&rsquo;re incredibly excited to be on the front lines.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.morgenthaler.com/">Morganthaler Ventures</a> invested $14 million in Charleston-based <a href="http://peoplematter.com/">PeopleMatter</a> earlier this year, and Kleiner Perkins has invested in two Greenville, SC companies, including <a href="http://www.proterra.com/index.php">Proterra</a>.</p>

<p>GSA Business, a local publication, <a href="http://www.gsabusiness.com/news/45945-venture-capitalists-take-a-peek-at-s-c">also says that</a> in order to attract more capital, _&ldquo;Companies and regions can up their chances of securing out-of-state venture capital. <strong>Regions need to focus on creating technology hubs</strong>, such as Charleston’s Digital Corridor or Greenville’s manufacturing hub of international companies.&rdquo;</p>

<blockquote><p>&ldquo;The regions also need to <strong>cultivate a skilled workforce, business community support and quality of life</strong>,&rdquo; venture capital executives said._</p></blockquote>

<p>The Iron Yard is doing just that, and we&rsquo;ve got exciting news around the corner. Stay tuned.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why Startups in South Carolina? Because We're One of the Top States for Business]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2012/10/24/why-startups-in-south-carolina-because-were-one-of-the-top-states-for-business/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T15:17:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.github.io/blog/2012/10/24/why-startups-in-south-carolina-because-were-one-of-the-top-states-for-business</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>South Carolina seems like an odd place to be luring entrepreneurs and launching startups. That is until you visit &ndash; our quality of life in the upstate wows travelers from around the country (most recently a few editors from TechCrunch).<strong> But that&rsquo;s not the whole story. </strong></p>

<p>Area Development just <a href="http://www.areadevelopment.com/Top-States-for-Doing-Business/Fall2012/Strong-Business-Labor-Climat-South-Carolina-789932.shtml">ranked South Carolina #2 overall</a> in the best places to do business&hellip;in the country. An excerpt from the article is below, but first, a celebration is in order. SC, we&rsquo;re proud of you and proud to be a part of what&rsquo;s going on. Cheers.</p>

<p><em>From the ranking report:</em></p>

<blockquote><p>South Carolina is on a roll — the Palmetto State brought in a total investment of $3.37 billion from new and expanding businesses in 2011. Manufacturing is also on the mend, with total exports up by 21 percent last year. These are just some of the reasons South Carolina was ranked second by the consultants among the Top States for Doing Business, up from fourth place in 2011.</p></blockquote>

<p>The consultants also ranked South Carolina second for its overall business environment and overall labor climate (tied) because of its competitive labor costs and leading work force development programs. This is a result of the state’s pro-active approach to building a ready and willing work force that provides the advanced skill sets companies need for their new operations. ReadySC, South Carolina’s work force development program, has trained more than 250,000 workers for nearly 2,000 companies.</p>

<p><em><a href="http://www.areadevelopment.com/Top-States-for-Doing-Business/Fall2012/Strong-Business-Labor-Climat-South-Carolina-789932.shtml">Read the full article here.</a></em></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
